Chentao Yang

Dr. of astrophysics















As a trained astrophysicist, I have a solid foundation in math and physics. My 10+ years experience in (data-analysis driven) observational astrophysics research has sharpened my data analysis skills and exploration spirits. I'm curious and versed in dissecting complex problems, while maintaining the balance intricate details with big-picture perspectives.

TOOL-SET











Shell (Unix/Linux), Julia, FORTRAN, Lang: IDL, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Astropy, Matplotlib, ...), Matlab, Mathematica

VS Code, Jupyter Lab, Git, 上TEX, LyX, **S/W:** Obsidian, Adobe Illustrator, FontLab MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint)...

LANGUAGE

English Full proficiency

Mandarin **Native French** Elementary **Swedish Beginner Beginner Spanish**

MISCELLANEOUS



Philosophy, Fiction, Science



🎏 Jazz, Classic, Soundtrack



Hiking, Citywalk



😘 Sci-fi, Indie, Mystery

KEY COMPETENCES

- **Experience:** 10+ Years of data analytic experience in academia.
- **Project management: 50+ Research Publications** in top international journals (incl. press release), with 1000+ Citations.
- Coding ability: 5+ Github Projects, 50+ Stars (using math tools like Bayesian/frequentist statistics/MCMC, and graphic design).
- Visualization & Storytelling & Communication: 12+ Oral **Presentations in top** international conferences (incl. invited).
- Writing skill & scientific excellence: 500+ hours Awarded PI Observing Telescope Time from 30+ proposals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctral Researcher in astrophysics (2021-current)

Chalmers tekniska högskola

- Analyzed large interferometric radio data sets of galaxies.
- Creative visualization of astronomical images and related physical parameters.
- Quantified data and interpreted results via mathematical & physical models.
- Leadership in international team for independent complete research projects.

Postdoctral Research Fellow in astrophysics (2017-2021)

European Southern Observatory (ESO)/Joint ALMA Observatory

- Prestigious fellowship in the leading astronomical research center, ESO (Chile).
- Hands-on with the most advanced ground-based observatory, ALMA.
- Independent research from ideas to publications.
- Leading international collaborations.

EDUCATION

PhD in Astrophysics (dual-diploma)

Université Paris-Saclay (2014-2017)

(Top 20 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (2013-2017) (Top 70 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

Master in Astrophysics

Beijing Normal Univesity (2010-2013)

Bachelor in Astronomy

Beijing Normal University (2006-2010)

(Graduate with distinguished honour, at both university and municipality levels)

SKILLS

Team work, Effective communication, Project management, Programming, Creative data visualization, Data intuition, Problem-solving, Critical thinking, Curiosity

AWARDS & PEER RECOGNITION

Referee & Expert Reviewer Committees

- Reviewer of several top internation astrophysical journals
- External reviwers of pretigous telescopes (JWST, HST...) & national funds (STFC...).

Several Scholarships and Funding Awards

- NAOC (National Astronomical Observatory of China) Scholarship
- National Undergraduate Innovative Test Program Grant (10k CNY)
- ESO Science Support Discretionary Fund (9k EUR)
- The LIA-Origins Short Visit Program Grant (3k EUR)

Fellowship

ESO Fellowship (Chile), 4-year independent research funding